L 与 T、D、N 的比较。当你学会正确发 L 时，你会感觉
L compared with T D and N. When you learn to pronounce the L correctly, you'll feel
它和 T、D、N 的相似性。实际上，舌头在这四个音中都处于同一位置，
its similarity with T D and N. Actually, the tongue is positioned in the same place
这四个音在口腔中的位置相同，都在牙齿后方。区别在于气流如何、
in the mouth for all four sounds, behind the teeth. The difference is in how and
从哪里出来。T 和 D 这两个音，是通过
where the air comes out. T and D. The sound of both T and D is produced by
让一股气流从舌尖上方出来发出的。N 音则
allowing a puff of air to come out over the tip of the tongue. N. The sound of N
是鼻音。舌头完全阻止气流从口腔出去，只允许
is nasal. The tongue completely all air from leaving through the mouth, allowing
气流从鼻子出去。说 N、L 时，你应该能感觉到舌头边缘
it to come out only through the nose. You should be able to feel the edges of your
碰到牙齿。发 L 时，舌尖
tongue touching your teeth as you say N, L. With the L, the tip of the tongue is
牢牢抵住牙齿后方的上颚，但舌头两侧
securely touching the roof of the mouth behind the teeth, but the sides of the
放下并绷紧。这就是 L 和 N 的区别。
tongue are dropped down and tensed. This is where L is different from N. With N,
发 N 时，舌头放松，覆盖牙齿后方周围的整个区域，
the tongue is relaxed and covers the entire area around the back of the teeth
发 L 时，舌头非常紧张，空气会从两侧出来。
so that no air can come out. With L, the tongue is very tense and the air comes out
刚开始时，夸张地摆出口腔位置会有帮助。
around its sides. At the beginning, it's helpful to exaggerate the position of the
伸出舌尖时，对着镜子看看自己。
tongue. Look at yourself in the mirror as you stick out the tip of your tongue
伸到前牙之间。舌头保持在这个位置，多说几次 L。
between your front teeth. With your tongue in this position, say L several times.
然后把舌头放回牙齿后方再试着说 L。听起来很复杂，
Then try saying it with your tongue behind your teeth, L. This sounds complicated,
但做起来比描述起来容易。不过，我们第一个练习必须专注于
but it's easier to do than to describe. Our first exercise, however, must focus on
区分这些声音。
differentiating the sounds.